# Anup Kumar

### **Statistician**

Statistics graduate having 2 years of experience with a passion for data analysis, visualization, and statistics. I'm excited to apply my passion for data science to the collaborative efforts of a Chevron team focused on insightful, high-quality data analytics and visualizations.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### John Snow Inc.

M&E Associate

New Delhi, India | April 2022 - current

- Data management of Universal Immunization Programme (UIP) support to Ministry of Health and Family Welfare using R.
- Assess Missed Opportunities for Simultaneous Vaccination in India Using Household Survey.
- Estimate the Infant target population for routine immunization using different statistical methods.
- Forecasting the Immunization coverage based on historical data using statistical methods.
- Developing the dashboard for routine immunization using R and Excel.
- Support the data requirement to Ministry of Health and Family Welfare.

### **Asian Development Research Institute**

Research Associate

Patna, India | Aug 2021 - Apr 2022

- Trend analysis of Air Pollution Collaboration with Norwegian Institute for Air Research and World Bank.
- Assisting in development visualization & delivery of R Shiny platform.
- Statistical modeling on air pollution, climate change and health data using Bayesian network.

#### The INCLEN Trust International

Data Manager

New Delhi, India | Nov 2020 - Aug 2021

- Lead the complete data management under the project titled "Establishing Demographic Development and Environmental Surveillance Site across different geographic location in the country" under the Dept. of Biotechnology, Government of India.
- Extensive raw data cleaning and management, along with quality assurance using STATA.
- Assisted other sites Pan-India in data collection and troubleshoot any data related issues.

#### anupkum9122@gmail.com

+918390627156

New Delhi, 110019



Linkedin



github

#### **SKILLS**

- R
- STATA
- SAS
- Advanced Excel

#### **EDUCATION**

# M.Sc. Biostatistics & Demography

International Institute for Population Science – May 2020

#### **B.Sc. Statistics**

University of Pune – May 2017

## STATISTICAL TECHNIQUES

- Linear Regression
- Logistic Regression
- Hypothesis Testing
- Clustering
- Decision Trees
- Random Forest
- PCA
- SVM
- Forecasting